<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RoboBrainz (group meeting)</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/categories/group-meeting.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:51:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Spring Semester - A whole bunch of TODOs</title><link>/posts/spring-semester-a-whole-bunch-of-todos/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spring semester's a month in and we hadn't updated the blog until now. Part of&lt;br&gt;
this was due to needing to find a new meeting time to meet with our advisor,&lt;br&gt;
polishing what we had for the cart, understanding how to denoise data using&lt;br&gt;
the FFT transformation of said data, and thumbing through the source code for&lt;br&gt;
the OpenBCI boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a few things that we discovered about using the OpenBCI boards in our project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We'd need to find a way to install the RFDuino library so the Arduino IDE&lt;br&gt;
can access it and properly program the dongle and the board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had to resort to stitching some vinyl onto some velcro to make applying the &lt;br&gt;
electrodes to ourselves a lot easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our master plan of powering the OpenBCI dongle with 3V from the Arduino pin&lt;br&gt;
didn't work. However, using a cut USB female cord does work to power it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At some point, we need to solder the headers for the OpenBCI boards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We'd need to find a way to write the firmware for the dongle so it can still talk&lt;br&gt;
to the OpenBCI GUI when plugged in. We're planning to have the dongle talk to the OpenBCI&lt;br&gt;
board as a middle man so the rover can receive data from the board wirelessly. This&lt;br&gt;
will be done over a serial established with two of the free pins on the dongle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the FFT calculations prove to be too much for the OpenBCI dongle, OpenBCI board,&lt;br&gt;
or the Arduino driving the cart, then we might need to get specialized hardware to do&lt;br&gt;
the FFT calculations. Chances of this are pretty slim though since we have plenty of Arduinos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arduino</category><category>faculty meeting</category><category>fft</category><category>group meeting</category><category>linux</category><category>openbci</category><category>rfduino</category><category>sdk</category><guid>/posts/spring-semester-a-whole-bunch-of-todos/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 02:28:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Installing Arch Linux in the Morken 212A Lab</title><link>/posts/installing-arch-linux-in-the-morken-212a-lab/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This took a while to document since I spread the installation out over three days (Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday specifically). The first few hours were spent trying to figure out why the &lt;br&gt;
LiveUSB's Arch Linux installer wouldn't boot. After inspecting the specs for all of the desktops, turns out it was just the computers' fault. The rest of the time was spent waiting for the packages to finish installing. The reason why we installed Arch Linux on these computers was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready access to the software we need (Arduino SDK and several dependencies for the Emotiv EPOC SDK) through the AUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phora has experience with Arch Linux packaging since she has an Arch Linux desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is easy to install only the packages needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the packages and packages we installed on the machines were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;base{,-devel} - Required for all Arch Linux machines. base-devel is an assumed prerequisite for using the AUR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kdebase - Easy to set up, ultra-customizable GUI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kdegraphics-{gwenview,okular} - Basic needs (image viewing, pdf viewing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gimp - For editing our concept art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dia - For editing our concept diagrams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;android-sdk{,-platform-tools} - In case we need to develop any android applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eclipse-android - In case we need to develop any android applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arduino - To start programming basic functionality in the robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;qtcurve - To keep all GUI widget themes consistent (this is important for the accessibility problems mentioned in &lt;a href="/posts/emotiv-epoc-sdk-experiments/"&gt;Emotiv EPOC SDK Experiments&lt;/a&gt;). Also makes changing the color and styling without much technical knowhow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kde-gtk-config - To keep all GUI widget themes consistent (this is important for the accessibility problems mentioned in &lt;a href="/posts/emotiv-epoc-sdk-experiments/"&gt;Emotiv EPOC SDK Experiments&lt;/a&gt;). Also makes changing the color and styling without much technical knowhow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;firefox - Basic needs (browsing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, an email just came in on 2014-11-07 stating that there was an unexpected turn of circumstances that provided. I applied for the refund, especially since we need the tests to be as early as possible. This will mean we have to look at alternate hardware while waiting for it to come in and/or develop any demo code for the EEG device earlier than expected (since the shipments are still applicable even after the refunds).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arch linux</category><category>emotiv</category><category>faculty meeting</category><category>group meeting</category><category>linux</category><category>workspace preparation</category><guid>/posts/installing-arch-linux-in-the-morken-212a-lab/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 03:22:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Group Meeting 1</title><link>/posts/group-meeting-1/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met today to get started on our requirements presentation and revising our requirements document. On top of needing to add class diagrams and sequence diagrams to it, we also noticed there were some use cases we should document. The most notable case was how we would let the user differentiate between a weak signal and confused input. We are also going to add drawings of each of our use cases to help clarify them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the presentation's mostly outlined. We'll get to filling in the content for the presentation over the weekend (including rudimentary storyboards for our presentations that'll likely be in *.xcf or *.svg format) and adding more documentation on our experiments with the Emotiv SDK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>group meeting</category><category>presentation</category><category>presentation prep</category><category>requirements</category><category>tech docs</category><guid>/posts/group-meeting-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 04:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>