<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RoboBrainz (requirements)</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/categories/requirements.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:51:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Advisor Meeting 2</title><link>/posts/advisor-meeting-2/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met with our advisor today from 10:20-10:50 and reported our progress.  Here were the major points of the meeting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="joan"&gt;Joan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had to work on the Requirements Document mostly on own during the weekend (and likely for next week too).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concerned about how the use cases mention AndroidEEG&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw the storyboards for the use cases without the Android app for the presentation. Including the Android app in the storyboards gives the illusion that Android middleman software will be essential to the functioning of the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the 1Sheeld may reduce the amount of Android code needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it as optional in case the middleman software makes it easier to write the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the use cases to optionally communicate with the 1sheeld for debugging purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found the data faker program in the Emotiv Epoc SDK (the binary's EmoComposer). Further comments about EmoComposer are in the &lt;a href="/posts/emotiv-epoc-sdk-experiments/"&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the data faker program be hooked up to the robot? That would be handy to debug the robot in case the headset readings get funky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up the presentation permissions for our advisor ASAP.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet with the advisor again (likely on own) at approximately 09:30 on 2014-10-28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since we'll need a decent draft of our presentation to show to our advisor, pretend that the presentation is due on Tuesday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further comments on the presentation will be emailed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="personal-notes-thatre-related-to-the-meeting"&gt;Personal notes that're related to the meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme for the website could be updated. It looks a little plain compared to &lt;a href="http://phora.github.io"&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start learning about how heuristic functions are used in AI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the &lt;a href="http://numenta.org/nupic.html"&gt;Numenta NUPIC code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should probably enable some form of commenting system on the blog. Will do so now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="drew"&gt;Drew&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unavailable for the meeting due to external circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checked up on the robot parts that came in the mail just in case anything happened to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ordered an LED(?) screen to get the free shipping. May come in handy later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>emotiv</category><category>faculty meeting</category><category>linux</category><category>presentation</category><category>requirements</category><category>robot</category><category>robot parts</category><category>sdk</category><guid>/posts/advisor-meeting-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 18:24:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Group Meeting 1</title><link>/posts/group-meeting-1/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met today to get started on our requirements presentation and revising our requirements document. On top of needing to add class diagrams and sequence diagrams to it, we also noticed there were some use cases we should document. The most notable case was how we would let the user differentiate between a weak signal and confused input. We are also going to add drawings of each of our use cases to help clarify them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the presentation's mostly outlined. We'll get to filling in the content for the presentation over the weekend (including rudimentary storyboards for our presentations that'll likely be in *.xcf or *.svg format) and adding more documentation on our experiments with the Emotiv SDK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>group meeting</category><category>presentation</category><category>presentation prep</category><category>requirements</category><category>tech docs</category><guid>/posts/group-meeting-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 04:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ordering Robot Parts</title><link>/posts/ordering-robot-parts/</link><dc:creator>pengor</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday we ordered the first set of parts for the robot from &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/"&gt;SparkFun Electronics&lt;/a&gt;, enough to get the robot moving. The only necessary component that we didn't purchase was an Arduino microcontroller, which we already have in our possession. Along with this board we went with a fairly basic robot design favoring simplicity when possible. The order consisted of:&lt;br&gt;
* 1 &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/12089"&gt;Multi-Chassis - 4WD Kit (Basic)&lt;/a&gt; - A rectangular chassis that has four independently-motorized wheels&lt;br&gt;
* 2 &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/9457"&gt;Motor Driver 1A Dual TB6612FNG&lt;/a&gt; - The intermediaries between the microcontroller (essentially the robot's brain) and the motors&lt;br&gt;
* 1 &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/12999"&gt;5 Pack of 5mm Addressable RGB LEDs&lt;/a&gt; - These will be used for debugging and user-feedback, different colors representing different messages&lt;br&gt;
* 1 &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/710"&gt;Graphic LCD 128x64&lt;/a&gt; - Mostly just tacked this on to get free shipping, but it could wind up in the project if we want another form of output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to get working on the hardware, but first up is preparing for our requirements presentation on next Thursday!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>emotiv</category><category>faculty meeting</category><category>linux</category><category>nikola</category><category>requirements</category><category>robot</category><category>robot parts</category><category>sdk</category><guid>/posts/ordering-robot-parts/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 23:40:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Meeting 1</title><link>/posts/advisor-meeting-1/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met with our advisor today from 10:20-10:50 and reported our progress. Here were the major points of the meeting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="joan"&gt;Joan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaged the Fedora version of the Research SDK for Arch Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found the most of the dependencies for the SDK. Still don't know what package provides libmkl_rt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emailed the support team about the packaging of the SDK so the developer team could fix this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's a fake data generator in the SDK lite for Windows and Mac (That's free!). So try to find the equivalent in the Linux SDK version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish work on not referencing the static copies of the library when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found a bug in nikola\plugins\task\sitemap__init__.py. It wasn't checking if directories were directories in a cross-platform manner. Will report this to the developers with an official patch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="drew"&gt;Drew&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Order the parts from SparkFun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chassis has built in motors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We may need a separate shield for driving the wheels?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably going to drive the motors with DC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settled on multicolor LEDs because single color LEDs can get confusing for debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>emotiv</category><category>faculty meeting</category><category>linux</category><category>nikola</category><category>requirements</category><category>robot</category><category>robot parts</category><category>sdk</category><guid>/posts/advisor-meeting-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:59:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Installing the Emotiv SDK</title><link>/posts/installing-the-emotiv-sdk/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we ordered the device this Saturday after the scholarship money came in... which'll take about two weeks from today. In the mean time, Joan downloaded the SDK to see how it's installed. Judging by a certain &lt;a href="http://emotiv.co/forum/messages/forum15/topic3749/message17131/?sphrase_id=7902#message17131"&gt;forum post on Emotiv's forums&lt;/a&gt;, I wasn't the only one shocked by how they provided the packaging. They provided an installer that downloads an installer to do the actual installer in an unsafe manner. Thankfully I knew enough about packaging to wrap it up in a much saner manner. You can find the PKGBUILD &lt;a href="https://github.com/RoboBrainz/Emotiv-Epoc-SDK-PKGBUILDs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my list of things to do is to minimize the references to extra copies of the libraries as much as possible. Second on my list of things to do is to make a proper *.spec file for Fedora installs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>PKGBUILD</category><category>emotiv</category><category>linux</category><category>please package properly</category><category>requirements</category><category>sdk</category><guid>/posts/installing-the-emotiv-sdk/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 19:20:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Requirements Document Meeting Logs</title><link>/posts/requirements-document-meeting-logs/</link><dc:creator>phora</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h2 id="meeting-notes"&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here were the major points from our meeting with our supervisor, Dr. Michael Turi, and our capstone instructor, Dr. George Hauser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="with-dr-turi"&gt;With Dr. Turi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The description part of the requirements document is similar to the goals section of the proposal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tasks we laid out should have a more pessimistic outlook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use case template we pasted into the document is fine. It might not hurt to include situations like, "What if the signal's fuzzy?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="with-dr-hauser"&gt;With Dr. Hauser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the large amount of unknowns with our project, the requirements might still be fuzzy. But that's okay since it's a draft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It'd be neat to get the equipment before the presentation for the requirements document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class project web page should be in the introduction or in a special section near the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="document-work-summary"&gt;Document work summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we continued working on the requirements document. Most of the work involved explaining requirements more technically and splitting up the tasks wherever they can go wrong. However, we're still a bit nervous that we may've not made the educational part of the description with the right amount of detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the amount of technicality for the rest of the goals might've either been too much (in cases where we knew how to expand it) or too little (in cases where we're &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; not sure how to deal with it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>faculty meeting</category><category>proposal to requirements</category><category>requirements</category><category>tech docs</category><guid>/posts/requirements-document-meeting-logs/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 19:33:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>